<cv-document>
    <personal>
        <first-name>Alexander</first-name>
        <last-name>Dovzhikov</last-name>
        <address>
            <country>Russia</country>
            <city>St. Petersburg</city>
            <street>pr.Slavy,52/1 ap.240</street>
        </address>
        <phone type="home">+7 812 453 0557</phone>
        <phone type="mobile">+7 921 949 2660</phone>
        <email>alexander.dovzhikov@gmail.com</email>
        <birthday>1979-09-10</birthday>
        <marital-status>Married</marital-status>
        <languages>
            <language type="native">Russian</language>
            <language type="fluent">English</language>
        </languages>
    </personal>
    <education>
        <university>
            <university-name>Saint Petersburg State University</university-name>
            <start-date>1996</start-date>
            <end-date>2001</end-date>
            <department>Mathematics and Mechanics Faculty</department>
            <specialty>Computer Science</specialty>
            <level>Master of Science</level>
            <thesis>Online Training Development System</thesis>
        </university>
    </education>
    <objective>Senior Java Developer / Technical Lead position in Financial Services area.</objective>
    <summary>
        <summary-item>Over 10 years of experience in software development</summary-item>
        <summary-item>Strong analytical skills and experience in Object Oriented concepts and programming techniques</summary-item>
        <summary-item>Strong mathematical background</summary-item>
        <summary-item>Experience in Derivatives Trading Systems development</summary-item>
        <summary-item>
            Extensive development experience in Java, J2EE, JSP, Servlet, EJB, JDBC, Struts,
            Spring Framework, Hibernate, XML, HTML, JavaScript for n-tier architecture
        </summary-item>
        <summary-item>
            Relational Database (RDBMS) concepts, database designing, normalization, PL/SQL,
            stored procedures, triggers and extensively worked with Oracle and MySQL
        </summary-item>
        <summary-item>
            Installation, configuration and administration knowledge of Apache Tomcat, Weblogic and Oracle
            Containers for J2EE (OC4J)
        </summary-item>
        <summary-item>Experience in Web services technologies like Apache Axis, SOAP, WSDL</summary-item>
        <summary-item>More than 5 years of experience working on Linux platform and shell scripting</summary-item>
        <summary-item>
            Hands-on experience leading all stages of system development efforts, including requirements
            definition, analysis, design, coding, implement reusable components, using third-party API,
            test-driven development, resolution of defects, integrate and test, build, deployment and support
        </summary-item>
        <summary-item>Mentor other members/juniors in the team</summary-item>
    </summary>
</cv-document>